My last video on the Gemini 3.0 model
being leaked caught a ton of people
finally testing out the model, and the
results y'all showed me were truly
insane. But I got some major new updates
on the release of this new Gemini 3.0
model, which could be coming as early as
October 9th, which is tomorrow. The
Google Deep team has also been dropping
hints about a release that will be
coming tomorrow. Prediction markets are
also pointing for the same release date
and internal teams like Jules have even
leaked meetings as well as calls around
the October 9th 10:00 a.m. PT time. Now,
we have even seen live streams that have
been set from Google Cloud, which will
be going live exactly at 10:00 a.m. PT.
Now, what makes this so exciting is the
pre-esting we've seen from the Gemini
3.0 Pro model. It's rumored to be a
state-of-the-art, and many are even
calling it the best AI model ever
released. Based on its performance
across nearly every benchmark test on
the ARK AGI 2 leaderboard, it lists the
Gemini 3.0 thinking model all the way at
the top, scoring an impressive result
that surpasses every single model. And
based on the generations I had showcased
in my last video, as well as with my
personal test, it is truly the best
model ever. It can handle 100hour tasks.
It can achieve parody with human experts
on GDP Evo. And from my current test,
this thing is super fast and insanely on
point. But today, we're going to be
actually taking a deeper dive and trying
to showcase more examples to showcase
this early preview of the Gemini 3.0.
But just take a look at the quality of
output. This is a web landing page for a
random site that was created in a single
shot. This is the type of quality you're
going to be able to expect from this new
Gemini 3.0 model, which looks like it is
proficient in coding and it delivers
state-of-the-art reasoning. And I know
you may be wondering, how are people
actually getting generations with the
Gemini 3.0? Well, the thing is the
Google team has been introducing a new
AB testing for this model where it's a
feature that they rolled out within
Google AI Studio where you need to just
simply select the Gemini 2.5 Pro. Then
you can send in any prompt that you want
the Gemini 3.0 to output and then you
can just run this. But make sure you
copy it cuz you have a chance that it
might not generate with the 3.0 and it
will just fall back and use the Gemini
2.5 Pro. But to get the generation from
the 3.0,
you will see two different model cards.
You can see there's only one here. So,
this is actually the 2.5 generating it,
but you're going to need to constantly
refresh and send in the same prompt over
and over again. It could take
approximately 50 times to actually get
the result that you're looking for. But
you'll see two different model cards pop
up and that's exactly when you'll get
the generation from the Gemini 3.0. And
you can see right here, I'm constantly
refreshing to get the correct
generation. Before we get started, I
just want to mention that you should
definitely go ahead and subscribe to the
world of AI newsletter. I'm constantly
posting different newsletters on a
weekly basis. So, this is where you can
easily get up-to-date knowledge about
what is happening in the AI space. So,
definitely go ahead and subscribe as
this is completely for free. You'll
notice that you'll get responses from
either the Gemini 3.0 Pro or the Gemini
3.0 Flash model. The Gemini 3.0 network
code shows up as the 2HT variant and
you'll definitely see the difference in
the quality of output. This is likely
the 3.0 Pro, but just take a look at a
couple of frontends that was developed
by this variant. It's capable of
generating beautiful frontends, and it's
seriously impressive and greatly
elevates code quality, especially for
front-end components compared to
something you'd get from Sonic 4.5 or
the predecessor 2.5 Pro. But now the
other variant you might see is the 5QA,
which is likely the Gemini 3.0 Flash.
And while the generations are still
quite good, they're slightly behind the
output of the 3.0 Pro. So in this demo,
we're taking a look at the Gemini 3.0
Pro's Deep Think output, specifically on
how it performs on creative visual
reasoning and code generation for 3D
structures. The prompt used here was to
create a pelican on a bike with voxil
art. And it's designed to test the
model's ability to understand multimodel
concepts and test its generation on
voxalbased 3D code for structured
output. And you can see that it was able
to accurately generate it. And Voxart
did a great job with spatial reasoning.
The code generation was quite accurate,
especially with vauil style or pixel
grid based designs. The concept
composition looks perfect. And you can
see there's also an aesthetic balance in
terms of what it did with the bridge as
well as the water. This overall shows
how impressive this model is in terms of
its coding ability with creative
interpretation and something only top
tier models are capable of pulling off.
This is a demo of the exoplanet core
visualization and this was fully
generated in a single shot with the
Gemini 3.0 Pro and you can see its
ability to generate complex scientific
visualizations from a text prompt. It
showcases the model's strength in
spatial reasoning and scientific
accuracy. You can see that it's able to
turn abstract planetary data into
realistic 3D style visuals. And this is
something that we've never seen with
other models. This is truly the best
Minecraft clone that I have seen that is
functional and with actual capabilities.
You can move around. You can even fly in
creative. You can place down different
blocks and you can even break it. And
remember, this was only generated with
Gemini AI Studio. Imagine it combined
with a coding agent. Its capabilities
are definitely going to be enhanced
further. FYI, this is the dev who has
put me on this new AB testing and he is
someone that I highly recommend that you
follow as he is posting AI breakthroughs
on a daily basis. Essentially, he had
generated an Xbox controller and SVG
code, which is super accurate to an Xbox
controller, but you can see how well it
is in terms of outputting SVG code in
all fronts, from designing, symmetry, as
well as quality. Here is the Gemini 2.5
Pro, the 2HT checkpoint, which was able
to complete the solution to use Samara,
the 554, the problem in just 3 minutes.
the same problem that was cited in the
Oxford and Cambridge paper claiming that
no large language model could actually
solve and even GBT 5 Pro reportedly took
around 14 minutes to produce a full
proof. So this demo is showcasing that
it was able to have the Gemini 3.0
handle advanced theorem solving and
step-by-step proofs that were previously
considered unsolvable by any language
model. It was able to showcase how well
the model is with deep mathematical
reasoning and symbolic logic. This one
definitely boggles my mind. The dev that
I was talking about had asked Gemini 3.0
Pro to create something around the
Cardartesev scale level three
civilization. Basically, it's a
hypothetical society that can harness
higher energy output of its galaxy. It's
pretty cool. But the kind of prompt this
is is going to test a model's ability
for creative scientific reasoning as
well as seeing how well it is in terms
of blending astrophysics, speculative
design, as well as visual imagination to
build a consistent and futuristic
concept. The generation here shown is
showcasing how Gemini can go beyond
simple descriptions and it actually
visualizes advanced cosmic engineering,
Dyson spheres, as well as interstellar
scale systems with realistic physics
behind them. If you like this video and
would love to support the channel, you
can consider donating to my channel
through the super thanks option below.
Or you can consider joining our private
Discord where you can access multiple
subscriptions to different AI tools for
free on a monthly basis, plus daily AI
news and exclusive content, plus a lot
more. There's a lot more to this, so I
definitely recommend you subscribe to
this dev's Twitter page. Make sure you
go ahead and take a look at whatever
we're posting on the second channel cuz
we're also going to be posting a couple
of insights on this tomorrow. Hopefully
it releases tomorrow in the morning, but
definitely stay tuned on that because
I'm definitely going to be posting
another video talking more about the
technical aspects and having it combined
with a coding agent. But that's
basically it guys for today's video. I
hope you enjoyed it. I'll leave all
these links in the description below so
that you can potentially even try it
within Google AI Studio. With that
thought, guys, thank you guys so much
for watching and supporting the channel.
Make sure you go ahead and check take a
look at the second channel, join the
newsletter, join our Discord, follow me
on Twitter, and lastly, make sure you
guys subscribe, turn on notification
bell, like this video, and please take a
look at our previous videos cuz there's
a lot of content that you'll truly
benefit from. But with that thought,
guys, have an amazing day, spread
positivity, and I'll see you guys really
shortly. He suffers.